all right let's do one more example what
we have here is now the integral of e to
the 2x on the top all divided by 1 plus
e to the 2x on the bottom so they figure
out what's my f here and what's my you
now one of the things that I can sort of
know right off the top is that when I
take the derivative of 1 plus e to the
2x I'm going to get twice eetu 2x and
there's this factor of 2 there that's a
bit confusing but but it sort of looks
like the top here is related off by a
factor of 2 but it's related to the
derivative of the bottom so let me
experiment with setting u to be that
denominator ok so how does that work
U is the 1 plus e to the 2x it's
derivative us and we said was that twice
either 2x DX
well if that's my you what's my app look
this looks like the function 1 divided
by u times D U but we're off by this
factor of 2 all right so that's the U
and the D U but what is going to be in
that case the F now if I think about
this expression the place where you
occurs is on the denominator so we think
my F looks like 1 divide it out by U and
if they set my F to be 1 over u that
means that they capital F the
antiderivative of the lowercase F is
just gonna be the natural logarithm of
the absolute value of U now why is this
the case well if we take the derivative
of the natural logarithm of the absolute
value of U we're going to get 1 divided
by u so indeed capital F is an
antiderivative of a lower case of F ok
so now if I take what my expression is
notice how I'm going to relate it so we
have that syndra we want to compute but
what I've done here is I've divided out
by a 2 and I've multiplied by a 2 and I
can multiply and divide by 2 that's just
x 1 that doesn't doesn't do anything but
the reason why I do it is because now
when I've got this 2 on the top even
though is cancelled down here to e to
the 2x DX 2 e to the 2x DX that is just
D u that is what I have done is managed
to write this as
1/2 the integral of 1 over u du u so we
get the 1/2 that just comes along for
the ride the integral of 1 over u
becomes the natural logarithm and I
evaluate it at U where u is this 1 plus
e to the 2x and finally I add in the
plus C so that is going to be my general
antiderivative to this funky expression
and it's worth noting that integration
in general is actually quite a bit
harder than differentiation most of
these functions that you can combine
with quotients and products and
compositions and exponents of the
elementary functions we've been talking
about e to the ax and sine and
polynomials we can just apply our rules
and take the derivatives of all of them
but the other way around is not quite so
simple some integrands when you take the
integral of some functions it's able to
be done because it can be manipulated to
look into one of these nice forms like
we have here with the substitution rule
but that is in general not the case and
there's all sorts of integrals where we
don't have a nice rule like this to be
able to apply